equitymaster.com 2018-12-24

# Privacy Policy | Equitymaster

Maintaining the privacy of user's information is important to us. This privacy statement outlines how we collect information from you, when you register as a user at [www.Equitymaster.com](http://www.equitymaster.com/) (site or website) or when you subscribe to our online services and what we do with that information. 

When you browse through the pages of the website, read or download information, we may collect, note or analyze details about your visit such as: 

  * Your server address 
  * Your operating system, top level domain name and the type of web browser you use 
  * The date and time of your visit to the website 
  * Whether you have visited the website previously 
  * What pages of the website you accessed and what you downloaded 
  * Your usage pattern and characteristics in order to measure interest in and use of various areas of the site. 

This information we collect relates to your server or PC rather than you yourself.

The information we collect will be used within Equitymaster to help us improve our online services keeping in mind your needs, and to help us to provide you faster navigation and access to the various sections of the website. We may disclose this information to other persons for these purposes or for related purposes, including to information technology companies who assist us in constructing, designing and maintaining the website. 

We will also collect your personal details including your credit card details (in case of payment through Auto debit mode) while registering you as a user or subscriber of our various online services, or for payment for services or when you wish to download certain documents from our website or if you email us with a comment or query. We will use your details: 

  * To send you the documents you have ordered 
  * To answer your comment or query 
  * To monitor our responses to you 
  * For our internal sales and marketing analysis 
  * To facilitate payment through Auto debit mode 

We may also contact you to follow up on your order or request, or to provide you with further information about our products and services which may be of interest to you. Where we need to send you any documents, we may disclose your personal details to the mailing houses, printers or document management providers which Equitymaster uses so that they can forward the documents to you on our behalf. 

We may share information we collect via the website to other members of the Equitymaster Group who may use the same to provide you with information on various products and services which may be of interest to you. 

If you want to find out what personal information (if any) we hold in respect of you which has been collected through the website, or if you wish to update or correct your personal information, please contact us.

### Collection of information

The user represents that he is fully aware that in the course of using this website or in the process of subscribing to the products and services or part of it, Equitymaster may obtain information relating to the user, including information about his/her credit card and personal information for facilitating payment on auto debit basis which is of a confidential nature. Equitymaster does not collect personal information about the user except when such users specifically provide such information on a voluntary basis. For example, such information may be collected through the registration process for subscribing to services or in connection with contest submission, message boards, suggestions & votings/ polling activities. This information may be stored by Equitymaster or its Affiliate and used by Equitymaster and will be kept confidential. Personal information on users will not be sold or otherwise transferred to unaffiliated third parties without the approval of the user. 

### Privacy commitments

Equitymaster is strongly committed to protecting the privacy of its users and has taken all necessary and reasonable measures to protect the confidentiality of the users information and its transmission through the world wide web and it shall not be held liable for disclosure of the confidential information when in accordance with this Privacy Commitment or in terms of the agreements, if any, with the users. Employees of Equitymaster will not discuss the business affairs of any user with any other employee, except on a strict need-to-know basis. 

### Use of Information

Equitymaster undertakes not to disclose the information provided by the users to any person, unless such action is necessary to:

  * Conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process such as requests of the government, court, tribunal, authority or other regulatory agency and/or required by any law; 
  * Protect and defend Equitymaster or its Affiliates' rights, interests or property; 
  * Enforce the terms and conditions under which its products and/or services are sold; or 
  * Act to protect the interests of Equitymaster, its Affiliates, or its members, constituents or of other persons. 

Equitymaster may use and/ or share the information provided by the users as it may deem necessary with its Affiliates and third parties for providing services and any service-related activities in order to serve you better. In this regard it may be necessary to disclose the user information to one or more agents and contractors of Equitymaster, and their sub-agents or sub-contractors, but such agents, sub-agents, contractors and sub-contractors will be required to use such information only for the stipulated services. 

Equitymaster may disclose the user's personal information to government, court, tribunals, authorities or other regulatory agency and/ or as may be required by the law to comply with their bonafide request. In either case Equitymaster shall be bound by and shall at all times have the legal right to disclose any or all personal information given by the user to it and Equitymaster shall not be held responsible or liable for any eventuality, loss or damage to the user that may arise out of such action on its part. 

Further, some of the user information is maintained in Equitymaster's marketing database. Equitymaster may contact a user either by post, or by telephone or e-mail primarily as a follow-up to the user's request/enquiry or to answer any questions. Equitymaster may also contact a user from time to time in respect of other products and services that may be of interest to users. If a user does not wish to receive information about these products or services, the user may simply contact Equitymaster.by phone, e-mail or post and communicate its desire not to receive information on these products or services. 

Equitymaster may inform advertisers of information on user's behavior and characteristics showing interest in various areas of the Equitymaster website as well as number of users that have been exposed to or clicked on their advertising banner. Equitymaster will provide only aggregate data from such analysis done by it to third parties. Also, users should be aware that Equitymaster may sometimes permit third parties to offer subscription and/or registration-based services through Equitymaster. Equitymaster is not responsible for any actions or policies of such third parties and users should check the applicable privacy policy of such party when providing personally identifiable information. 

### Opt-Out

If, at any time after registering for information or subscribing to any of our services, you wish to discontinue receiving information from us or you wish to opt out of our marketing or promotional emails, phone calls or discontinue receiving any other direct communication from us, please either click on the "unsubscribe" link available in the service/promotional/marketing emails or send us your request to unsubscribe at [info@equitymaster.com](mailto:info@equitymaster.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy%20Unsubscribe)

### Policy against advertising Equitymaster website using unsolicited email messages

Equitymaster ensures that all emails promoting [www.equitymaster.com](http://www.equitymaster.com/) or its services or the domains owned by it are sent only to subscribers who have agreed to receive such messages. Equitymaster prohibits any advertising of its brand and Website using unsolicited email messages. Any non compliance with this policy would cause partnership termination and/or affiliate account termination.

If you feel that you have received unsolicited emails from Equitymaster and would like to register a compliant, please contact us at [info@equitymaster.com](mailto:info@equitymaster.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy%20Unsubscribe). We will on a best effort basis investigate all complaints related to unsolicited email messages.

### Security

The user shall cooperate with Equitymaster in order to ensure the security of the information, and we recommend that the users necessarily choose their passwords carefully such that no unauthorized access is made by a third party. The users should undertake not to disclose their password to anyone or keep any written or other record of the password such that a third party could access it. 

### Payment through credit card

In case of subscription to services through online card payments including on auto debit, Equitymaster may obtain private information from the Subscriber including but not limited to date of birth, card number, card expiry date and such other details as may be required by the online payment gateway or as required under any law for the time being in force. 

In such cases, Equitymaster shall take all measures including following such security practices and procedures designed to protect all private information obtained from the Subscriber from unauthorised access, damage, use, modification, disclosure or impairment, as may be deemed necessary and reasonable or as may specified by any law for the time being in force. 

### Cookies Policy

Users are informed that non-personal information and data may be automatically collected through the use of "cookies."

The detailed Cookie Policy may be read below:

#### What are Cookies:

"Cookies" are small text files a web site can use to recognize repeat users, facilitate the user's ongoing access to and use of the site and allow a site to track usage behavior and compile aggregate data that will allow content improvements and targeted advertising.

Cookies are not programs that come onto a user's system and damage files. Generally, cookies work by assigning a unique number to the user that has no meaning outside the assigning site.

#### Types of Cookies used:

#### _First-party cookies_

These are the cookies that belong to us and that we place on your device or are those set by a website that is being visited by you at the time. We use these cookies as they are absolutely necessary to provide you Equitymaster's services. If you choose to opt out of these cookies, then we may not be able to provide you services.

#### _Third-party cookies_

These cookies are those that another party places on your device through our site (For e.g. advertising agencies may place their cookies on our website which will collect tracking information and serve you with advertisements). We do not control these third-party cookies and their use may be governed by the privacy policies of the third parties employing these cookies. To learn about these cookies and to disable or reject third-party cookies, please refer to the relevant third party’s website.

#### _Persistent Cookies_

Persistent cookies are stored on a user’s device even after termination of a browsing session. It helps in recalling the preferences or actions of the user. Persistent cookies are used for a variety of purposes such as retaining the visitor’s language and regional preference(s) at the end of each browsing session. We use services of third-party analytics service provider to analyze cookies to carry out a behavioral analysis in order to enhance user experience and convenience, and also to provide targeted and relevant content to visitors. Depending on the type and settings of your browser, cookies may be accepted by default. You may change the settings of your browser to delete existing cookies or prevent future cookies from being automatically accepted. If you disable cookies, certain parts and functions of our website may not be available. You can learn more about cookies at www.aboutcookies.org.

#### _Session Cookies_

Session cookies remain only as long as a browsing session is active, and are intended to avoid user inconvenience during browsing. These cookies allow websites to link the actions of a user during a browser session and expire at the end of the browsing session. Session cookies also assist the user in navigating the website, and allow the user to access secure parts of the webpage when logged in.

    * #### How do we use cookies?

We use cookies to ensure you have the best browsing experience on our website. We also use Cookies to provide you various subscription services on our website.

    * #### Do these cookies collect personal data/identify me?

Most types of cookies track consumers via their Device ID or IP address therefore they may collect personal data.

Based on the type of cookies used by the relevant third-party, the information these cookies collect may include personal data but they may not be able to directly identify you as an individual or have any of your personal information such as Name, E-mail id or Mobile number.

    * #### How do I refuse or withdraw my consent to the use of Cookies?

If you do not want cookies to be dropped on your device, you can adjust the setting of your Internet browser to reject the setting of all or some cookies and to alert you when a cookie is placed on your device. For further information about how to do so, please refer to your browser 'help' / 'tool' or 'edit' section for cookie settings with respect to your browser that may be Google Chrome, Safari, Mozilla Firefox etc.

Please note that if your browser setting is already setup to block all Cookies (including strictly necessary Cookies) you may not be able to access or use all or parts of functionalities of our Sites.

If you want to remove previously-stored Cookies, you can manually delete the Cookies at any time. However, this will not prevent the Sites from placing further Cookies on your device unless and until you adjust your Internet browser setting as described above.

#### Categorization of Cookies:

    * #### Strictly Necessary/Technical:

These cookies are necessary for the website to function and cannot be switched off in our systems. They are usually only set in response to actions made by you which amount to a request for services, such as setting your privacy preferences, logging in or filling in forms. You can set your browser to block or alert you about these cookies, but some parts of the site will not then work.

    * #### Analytical/Performance Cookies:

These cookies allow us to count visits and traffic sources so we can measure and improve the performance of our site. These cookies track what type of articles are most frequently visited and which locations we receive most of our visitors from. These Cookies include, for example, Google Analytics cookies.

    * #### Targeting Cookies:

These cookies may be set through our site by our advertising partners. They may be used by those companies to build a profile of your interests and show you relevant adverts on other sites. They do not store directly personal information, but are based on uniquely identifying your browser and internet device. If you do not allow these cookies, you will experience less targeted advertising.

    * #### Social Media Cookies:

These cookies are set by a range of social media services that we have added to the site to enable you to share our content with your friends and networks. They are capable of tracking your browser across other sites and building up a profile of your interests. This may impact the content and messages you see on other websites you visit. If you do not allow these cookies you may not be able to use or see these sharing tools.

### Third Party Advertising

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements on this site and other sites about goods and services that may be of interest to you. 

Please note that this Privacy Statement does not extend to third party sites linked to this website. 

### Amendments

Equitymaster reserves the right to modify the whole or some sections of this Privacy Statement at any time. Please check this statement from time to time for any changes.

### References

  * to 'you, 'your' and 'yours' are references to the person(s) accessing this website.
  * to 'we', 'us' and 'our' are references to mean individually and collectively Equitymaster, Quantum, Agora & its directors, officers and employees.

### Contact

You may contact us at:   
103, Regent Chambers,   
Above Status Restaurant,   
Nariman Point, Mumbai - 400 021,   
India. 

Telephone: 91-22-6143 4055 

Fax: 91-22-2202 8550 

Email: [info@equitymaster.com](mailto:info@equitymaster.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy%20Unsubscribe)
